# Vinay B S

Software Solutions Engineer - Cisco

## Summary

I'm a quick learner and very enthusiastic in learning and implementing new technologies. I have been able to effectively multi-task and handle multiple projects simultaneously without compromising on the quality of work. Working with the open source community for the OpenStack project and mentoring experience has helped me to gain good collaboration skills. I enjoy taking on challenges and applying my skills to solve problems effectively.

## Experience

#### Software Systems Engineer at Cisco

October 2016 - Present (6 months)

As an SSE in the APJ GSP Infrastructure Programmability Centre of Excellence team, responsible for designing and building solutions using the programmatic capabilities of Cisco products. These solutions will be offered for Proof of Concept or demonstration to Service Provider customers.

#### Software Development Engineer at Cisco

February 2015 - October 2016 (1 year 9 months)

As an SDE, involved in the development of Cisco IMC Supervisor. IMC Supervisor is a Java based tool for monitoring and managing Cisco standalone Rack Servers upto a scale of 1000 servers in a Data Center. Also responsible for design and development of Cisco UCS plugins for Chef.

## QA Automation & OpenStack Engineer at Cisco

September 2013 - January 2015 (1 year 5 months)

As a QA engineer, built an automation framework for Cisco UCS PowerTool using powershell and Tcl scripting. Worked on cloud deployment using OpenStack, which is an open source cloud computing platform for public and private clouds. Also mentored an intern in my team and gained good experience in guiding and collaboration.

#### **Software Engineering Intern at Dell**

February 2013 - April 2013 (3 months)

Worked on developing a powershell based automation famework for validating the Dell feature management pack, which is a plugin for Microsoft SCOM.

## **Test Scores**

#### eLitmus pH test

January 2013 Score:94.09

eLitmus is India's leading Hiring Potential Test which measures the employ-ability of the candidates through verbal, problem solving and quantitative tests.

## Projects

#### **Cisco IMC Supervisor**

February 2015 to Present

Members: Vinay B S

As an SDE, involved in the development of Cisco IMC Supervisor. IMC Supervisor is a Java based tool for monitoring and managing Cisco standalone Rack Servers in a Data Center. Agile methodology was followed in this software development.

## **OpenStack**

February 2014 to Present

Members: Vinay B S

Contributor to OpenStack Ironic project (an opensource project). Ironic service in OpenStack is used to provision baremetal servers. The Ironic service uses various concepts in virtualization and cloud deployment to enroll the baremetal servers and use them as computing resources in OpenStack.

#### **Powertool Automation Framework**

September 2013 to January 2014

Members: Vinay B S

Developed an Automation framework for validation of Cisco UCS Powertool. The framework is based on Tcl and Powershell scripts. XML is used in the backend for storing the results and creating the test reports. The parameter value generation for the ~1500 commands in powertool was also automated.

#### **Classroom Assistance for the Blind**

February 2013 to June 2013

Members: Vinay B S

Development of an image processing based system which will help the visually disabled students to be a part of normal classroom teaching

## Heart Rate Remote data logger

February 2014 to Present

Members: Vinay B S, Harsha Basavaraj, Mohammed Salman

To build a system capable of measuring the heartbeat rate of a person and logging it on to a remote server (xively.com) automatically in real time. The device at the user end was built using a simple IR sensor for detecting heart rate which was processed using Arduino and data so obtained was logged to remote server using GSM module.

#### Stalker

January 2012 to Present

Members: Vinay B S, Bhargava Sreekantappa Gayathri, Tejas Ps, Yashdeep Umesh

The goal of this project was to make an autonomous slave robot to follow the path traversed by another autonomous master robot. The master robot is a line follower bot. Communication between the slave and master was through Zigbee Trans-reciever. (Developed for Kshitij-2012, IIT Kharagpur)

## Cisco UCS integration for Chef

2016 to Present

Members: Vinay B S

Design and development of Cisco UCS plugins for Chef. Responsible for scoping, designing and coding of plugins which will enable customers to manage Cisco servers using Chef.

## Volunteer Experience

#### Blood donation camp at Rotary club

Languages

**English** (Full professional proficiency)

**Kannada** (Native or bilingual proficiency)

## **Publications**

Classroom Assistance for Blind (National Conference on Information Technology, Communications, and Signal Processing (CISP 2013))

CISP 2013 March 1, 2013

Authors: Vinay B S, Tejas Ps, Yashdeep Umesh, Shreyas Sreenivas

## Skills & Expertise

**Software Solutions** 

**Solution Development** 

**Solution Implementation** 

**Software Integration** 

**Cloud Computing** 

Virtualization

**Web Development** 

**Web Application Design** 

**Web Framework** 

Flask

HTML

**Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)** 

**JavaScript** 

**Python** 

Java

**OpenStack** 

Chef

**Docker** 

**Debugging** 

Linux

**Testing** 

**Cisco UCS** 

**Networking** 

**XML** 

**Programming** 

**SQL** 

**Software Engineering** 

**Software Development** 

**Cisco UCS Director** 

Cisco CloudCenter

**VMware** 

**API Development** 

**JSON** 

## Education

## R. V. College of Engineering, Bangalore

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Electrical, Electronics and Communications Engineering, 2009 - 2013 Activities and Societies: Robotics club, organized technical events in fests, conducted technical workshops MES Vidyasagar PU College

Pre-University, Science, 2007 - 2009

## **Interests**

New technologies, Cloud computing, Virtualization, Badminton, Travelling

# Vinay B S

Software Solutions Engineer - Cisco



## 2 people have recommended Vinay

"Vinay & I worked together on multiple releases of Cisco IMC Supervisor, after he became the third person in our team who was assigned to work on this product (I was the second). Having been informed that Vinay had prior scripting experience in a peer QA team, I was pleasantly surprised to see him pick up the nuances of Java development at a fairly rapid pace. He was soon able to build a solid understanding of Cisco IMC Supervisor's architecture, design & code base. This led to several important feature contributions from him in subsequent releases. He possessed the ability to quickly understand the feature ask and prototype a near-production-quality implementation of the same, always faster than expected! Also worth mentioning are the efforts & thoughts which he put into setting up, maintaining & running a test bed for performance evaluation & testing of Cisco IMC Supervisor. As the product's user base increased, the team was swamped with several escalations related to scale & performance. His contributions towards investigating some of them and facilitating a technical solution were crucial to the success of future releases. I highly recommend Vinay as an efficient, quick-thinking, innovative & cheerful software engineer for any team or organization. He would thrive in a fast-paced environment at both startups and larger companies."

— Vivek K Indrayan, Software Engineer - Cisco UCS (Compute Systems Product Group), Cisco, managed Vinay indirectly at Cisco

"Vinay joined my team as a new college hire but he learnt new technologies very quickly. He designed and developed Powertool Automation Framework without much supervision. He also worked on Openstack Ironic driver where he ramped up very quickly on this new software after spending long work hours. He is always ready to put in extra-time. He is a great team player. Also, he has very good communication skills and is a great asset to any team."

— Jatin Sharma, Engineering Manager, Cisco Systems, managed Vinay at Cisco

Contact Vinay on LinkedIn